<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Personal | Dr. Zhipeng Huang</title><link>https://zhipeng-huang.netlify.app/tag/personal/</link><atom:link href="https://zhipeng-huang.netlify.app/tag/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Personal</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://zhipeng-huang.netlify.app/media/icon_hu09119d9643d37a87f069413482cf4469_5405_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Personal</title><link>https://zhipeng-huang.netlify.app/tag/personal/</link></image><item><title>PhD positions on femtoelectrochemistry</title><link>https://zhipeng-huang.netlify.app/post/email_2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhipeng-huang.netlify.app/post/email_2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>Multiple PhD positions are available in the Faculty of Physics at the University of Duisburg-Essen in Duisburg, Germany, under the supervision of Prof. Dr. R. Kramer Campen and Dr. Zhipeng Huang within the general topic of femtoelectrochemistry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our group, we address fundamental questions in the mechanism of (photo)electrocatalytic chemistry by conducting experiments in which we initiate and probe electron (and coupled proton) transfer with femtosecond timescales using nonlinear optical and optoelectric tools. In the near term, this work will involve the description of water electrolysis and small organic molecule oxidation on Pt and Co-Ferrites. In pursuit of such understanding, experiments will be conducted both at well-defined surfaces in ultra-high vacuum and under potential-control within thin film spectroelectrochemical cells.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All positions offer contracts for three years with possible extension based on good performance and availability of funds, and will be paid according to the public service’s wage agreement (E13 TV-L, 66% in year 1 and 75% thereafter).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Applicants should have a Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in physics, chemistry, materials science, chemical engineering, or a related field with a good GPA (1.5 or better in the German system or equivalent). Applicants should have experience in experimental physics or chemistry and good English language skills. Programming experience, ideally Labview or Julia, and experience with ultrafast lasers, would both be a bonus, but are not required. Depending on interest, it is anticipated that the successful applicants will become graduate students in either the Integrated Graduate School Solvation Science (a part of the German Research Foundation-funded RESOLV (Ruhr Explores Solvation) Cluster of Excellence) or the Integrated Research Training Group “Understanding Oxidation Catalysis” (a part of the German Research Foundation-supported Collaborative Research Center 247 “Heterogeneous Oxidation Catalysis in the Liquid Phase”). In either case, the association offers supplementary workshops, travel support for meetings, and support for internships with international collaborators.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To initiate an application or to obtain further information, please contact Dr. Huang (&lt;a href="mailto:zhipeng.huang@uni-due.de">zhipeng.huang@uni-due.de&lt;/a>) or Prof. Campen (&lt;a href="mailto:richard.campen@uni-due.de">richard.campen@uni-due.de&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The application should include a curriculum vitae, transcripts of grades from Bachelor and Master studies, title and abstract of Bachelor and Master thesis (if applicable), a list of publications (if applicable), the contact information of at least two professional references, and a brief statement on why you would like to pursue your studies in the group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks very much for forwarding this message to any potentially interested candidates.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>