<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>publication | Dr. Zhipeng Huang</title><link>https://zhipeng-huang.netlify.app/category/publication/</link><atom:link href="https://zhipeng-huang.netlify.app/category/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>publication</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://zhipeng-huang.netlify.app/media/icon_hu09119d9643d37a87f069413482cf4469_5405_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>publication</title><link>https://zhipeng-huang.netlify.app/category/publication/</link></image><item><title>Our latest paper, titled 'Integration of conventional surface science techniques with surface-sensitive azimuthal and polarization dependent femtosecond-resolved sum frequency generation spectroscopy', is out now in Review of Scientific Instruments</title><link>https://zhipeng-huang.netlify.app/post/2024_rsi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhipeng-huang.netlify.app/post/2024_rsi/</guid><description>&lt;p>The renowned physicist Wolfgang Pauli once said, &amp;ldquo;God made the bulk; the surface was invented by the devil.&amp;rdquo; Studying the properties of surfaces is challenging, especially their ultrafast non-equilibrium dynamics. However, studying surfaces is important, as they lay the foundation for heterogeneous catalysis, heterostructure devices, 2D materials, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Femtosecond angle-resolved photoemission, ultrafast low-energy electron diffraction, ultrafast grazing incidence X-ray scattering, ultrafast infrared reflection and surface-enhanced Raman spectroscopy have been used and play main roles in studying the ultrafast non-equilibrium dynamics of surfaces. If the surfaces are buried, for example, in solid-bulk liquid interfaces or heterostructure bulk junctions, applying electron-based ultrafast characterization techniques to these systems can be challenging due to their small penetration depth. Ultrafast sum-frequency generation nonlinear spectroscopy (SFG) shows its advantage for these systems. SFG probes the second-order susceptibilities χ(2) of the materials. It equals zero for centrally symmetric bulk materials, thus providing surface and interface sensitivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this contribution, we reported the development of an ultra-high vacuum setup that integrates conventional surface science techniques with azimuthal and polarization-dependent, femtosecond time-resolved sum-frequency generation spectroscopy and scanning sum-frequency generation microscopy. With a series of proof-of-principle measurements of CO adsorbed on Pt(111) and of the clean Ag(111) surface, we demonstrate that the setup offers 34 fs temporal resolution to perform time-resolved SFG spectroscopy, sufficient manipulator stability to perform scanning SFG microscopy on ~40 μm length scales, and flexible sample rotation to perform azimuthal-dependent SFG spectroscopy. This setup allows for the full characterization of the nonlinear susceptibility under equilibrium and femtosecond optically excited non-equilibrium conditions, as well as temperature control and sample preparation/characterization of conventional UHV setups.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Building a setup combining several ultrahigh vacuum chambers with sophisticated laser beam paths from scratch is challenging. We hope this contribution will be of interest to scientists in the fields of surface science, physical chemistry, materials science, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0205278" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the link&lt;/a> of the publication. The full article can be found at &lt;a href="https://zhipeng-huang.netlify.app/publication/rsi_2024/RSI_2024.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this link&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Our latest paper, titled 'Rubber-like elasticity in laser-driven free surface flow of a Newtonian fluid', is out now in PNAS</title><link>https://zhipeng-huang.netlify.app/post/pnas_2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhipeng-huang.netlify.app/post/pnas_2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>Have you ever imagined blowing bubbles in a vacuum environment with a laser pulse?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our recent paper, published in PNAS, describes the method of generating/blowing glycerol bubbles under vacuum using picosecond infrared laser pulses (through laser-induced spallation) and imaging them with a nanosecond pulse illuminated bright-field optical microscope. Through the analysis of the bubble dynamics, we uncovered a transient rubber-like elasticity in the thin liquid glycerol film. In a previous study, we demonstrated the applicability of these thin liquid bubbles/films for liquid ultrafast electron diffraction experiments. The method can also be very useful in the field of rheology to reveal the mechanical properties of liquids.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We constructed the setup and obtained these experimental results over three years ago. Many thanks to all the co-authors, Meghanad Kayanattil, Dr. Sascha W. Epp, and Djordje Gitaric, for the careful analysis and for finally getting it published, as well as for the support from the MPI for the Structure and Dynamics of Matter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is &lt;a href="https://www.pnas.org/doi/10.1073/pnas.2301956120" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the link&lt;/a> of the publication. A concise news report on our recent PNAS paper can be found on &lt;a href="https://www.mpsd.mpg.de/735686/2023-06-glycerol-kayanattil?c=2736" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the webpage&lt;/a> of MPI for the Structure and Dynamics of Matter and &lt;a href="https://phys.org/news/2023-06-rubber-like-elasticity-liquid-glycerol.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Phys.org website&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Our recent publication "Picosecond infrared laser driven sample delivery for simultaneous liquid-phase and gas-phase electron diffraction studies" was selected as a featured article in Structural Dynamics</title><link>https://zhipeng-huang.netlify.app/post/pirl_optical_electron_imaging_setup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhipeng-huang.netlify.app/post/pirl_optical_electron_imaging_setup/</guid><description>&lt;p>We successfully coupled a laser-driven molecular beam with a table-top femtosecond electron gun and a pulsed bright-field optical microscope to image laser produced gas-phase and liquid-phase samples by pulsed electrons and photons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With varying the ablation laser fluence or the time delay, we can deliver either gas-phase or liquid-phase samples to the electron/light pulse interaction point. Our methodology provides time separable nanoscale liquid phase and gas-phase sample delivery under identical conditions to enable atomic imaging using electron sources and determination of solvation effects and is promising to extend to large biomolecules under either isolated gas-phase or solvated environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is the pdf link of the publication (&lt;a href="https://aca.scitation.org/doi/pdf/10.1063/4.0000159" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://aca.scitation.org/doi/pdf/10.1063/4.0000159&lt;/a> ). It was selected as a featured article by the editors.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>